uh there are like three years gap
between when I started background and
when I started getting money from
McDonald's
[Music]
awesome hey Sergey how's it going hello
very good
awesome uh well for those of you who
don't know this is uh circuit ocean AKA
baggy Pro uh he's one of the big mobile
hackers in the scene and today we're
going to be sitting down just me and him
to have a little discussion about mobile
hacking and what led you on your path
and all sorts of things so um why don't
you go ahead and give a little
introduction
um
I'm bike room
like some time ago I was number one
hiker in Google Play security Rewards
program
um in the past year a number hacker in
Samsung program and I'm also the founder
of over security it's mobile scanners
for Android and for iOS applications
awesome yeah yeah well we're going to
talk about all those different things I
have I have some notes written here so
I'm excited to to pick each of those
apart but why don't we uh why don't we
just get started with
um sort of like how you even got into
Mobile hacking because I'm a mobile
hacker myself and there's really not a
ton of us or if there are we we're very
uh quiet and in the shadows sort of
types of things so uh what was sort of
your introduction into Mobile hacking
how did you how did you get started
that's actually very and I didn't plan
this and I had no any experience with
mobile hacking but when I was 18 I was a
student in a university I was studying
maths and like a low-level programming
like assembler programming and so on and
when I was in school I was working for
American company as a QA engineer and I
wanted to find like a joke not for money
not because of money but to get some
experience like real practice
and I was looking for a job I was coming
to co-engineer uh interviews I was
coming to uh like
the C plus plus programming interviews
and my actual resume was about Junior C
plus plus developer
yes and I was clicking like everywhere
like a completely come to interview and
companies uh were replying to me and
some company uh they had uh like three
jobs it's a Unix security Guy mobile
security guy and uh like web security
guy and I clicked I want to be unique
security guy because it looks uh it
looked like more hard and that's why I
think this
yeah they called me uh they told they
liked my resume and they want me to come
to their office and they asked I believe
what they want to do I told Unix
security they told no uh but they want
to pick me for mobile security and
that's how I started working with mobile
security oh wow okay so like a totally
completely literally like almost by
chance yes wow okay and so you did that
for I assume a number of years and then
when did you find bug bounty
um so actually
um this company was doing uh uh like
Consulting and selling security products
and um like all of uh my friends in the
company like colleagues they were doing
but Bounty and like their salary was
like one or two thousand dollars per
month but they were getting like ten
thousand dollars after months for back
bounties and they worked in the office
just because of community and I said oh
I want this but I was like 18 years old
and I had no idea how to get money from
bug bounties and that's why I was trying
like 10 times 20 times until it
succeeded
oh wow okay that's crazy so do any of
those people still hack and were they
also mobile hackers or did they do they
do differences like whip crackers so
actually I believe uh the most people
they hunt for like uh specific
vulnerability category for example
exercise or browsers or mobile browsers
um and so on
I know people that that uh hunt for x6a
only so okay for mobile box
wow that's really interesting okay so
you you know you knew these co-workers
they were doing bug Bounty they
encouraged you I had a very similar
experience as well where uh one of my
co-workers was somebody who did bug
Bounty and they were like hey you should
you should try this bug Bounty thing out
and I was like oh okay that looks
interesting yep but um it doesn't work
immediately because I was coming to
different backgrounds first of all I had
no any experience second of all
um like in 2015 companies didn't believe
that mobile box exists
I'm submitting the vulnerability and
they say it's not a vulnerability it's
so true oh man this is like I talk about
this a little bit but yeah this is this
is something that honestly only over the
last couple years like maybe the last
five years has it really started to
change a lot where the like risk
assessment for mobile bugs has gotten a
lot better because it for the longest
time they were just like oh you can't
exploit this because you have to be on
the device or you'd have to have
physical proximity to stuff like that
and then it was like you know yes but
there that is a non like that happens
now like where you know malware is a
real thing like people install random
apps from the internet all the time so
it's not like a non-zero scenario where
it can't happen
yeah because there are like a number of
attack vectors for example a completely
remote like from local network
from physical closeness from physical
access to the device and from local
access yes it's not the AP1 but it's a
vulnerability anyway
yeah yeah absolutely so you then started
doing bug money and were you always
doing the Google vrp or what what ended
up getting you to the number one spot
there I know
so there are like three years gap
between when I started bhagwanji and
when I started getting money from bug
bounces
yes in summer time I got a visit to Cs
and that's why I wanted to visit I
wanted to rent a Mustang uh mustn't
convertible GT model and it was like
pretty expensive
um as a student I didn't have enough of
money to like afford it and that's why I
said like backbang let's try again and
before that I submitted like attentive
vulnerabilities that got rated is not
the security vulnerability and I really
enjoy it like I was submitting like a
lot of vulnerabilities I was describing
them they carefully and it worked I
remember a vulnerability in jira it's a
it was used in an SDK that was
vulnerable to that theft of arbitrary
files and I submitted it to Gora it's
disclosed in my hacker run profile I
submitted to jira they fix it and like
from only one this specific
vulnerability I got like ten thousand
dollars and it was yeah I have enough
money
to afford my trip and everything else
that you can rent the Mustang yeah
that's awesome that's awesome it's all
about setting goals you know I I love
that I love just like having a specific
goal in mind and then you just like
focus on that and just like hone in your
energy all towards that one thing yeah
because if it didn't work I had to rent
I don't know Hyundai
I can't be doing that
that's awesome
um so you mentioned uh you mentioned
that you're the number one hacker on
Samsung right now is that is that right
yeah
yeah so
um tell me a little bit about that
because Samsung is uh I don't think I've
actually ever hacked on Samsung and they
run an independent program right it's
like totally operated by them so what
what is uh what what was that process
like what led you to start hacking so
much on Samsung and uh what are sort of
the pros and cons of working directly
with the company like that
actually it was like super random
because I had my I have like in my life
I'm using iPhones but I also have
Android devices and like the test
vulnerabilities and so on and I'm using
a Samsung for this purpose and um I
thought like yes I'm not using it like
every day but I still use them soon and
that's why it's a good Target first of
all and second of all um I had no idea
about fragmentation and Android vendors
but it appeared that uh Android devices
are completely different
if you take a pixel device if you take a
Samsung device if you take like Excel me
device they're completely different from
like vulnerabilities perspective and
that's why I was curious uh like
are there any vulnerabilities but it
appears there are a lot of them like
device specific vulnerabilities or
vendor specific vulnerabilities
do you find it difficult to sort of work
with that attack service or did you
originally find it difficult because I
imagine as you're uh trying to attack
something like pixel or Samsung like the
the scope changes quite a bit and also
those attack vectors change quite a bit
where you have to start thinking about
the threat model differently sort of
from like
a more of a consumer perspective right
where where are the vulnerabilities
within the system as a whole that you
can exploit uh versus just like specific
applications or specific scenarios
um so how can you talk a little bit
about that
um you could have like I love Christian
but the answer is no yeah everything is
simpler because uh the application I
read in the in Java not in kotlin and is
there no any obfuscation and that's why
it's much easier to account for
vulnerabilities
okay that wow that is not what I was
expecting actually so so for some
context for like people are listening
um I I think a lot of people may be
unfamiliar with this but most apps uh
nowadays I'd say probably I don't know
at least 30 percent are written in
kotlin right
um
so I believe for like uh
80 of applications
their Java in kotlin based so
I'm talking about like a big modern Rich
application yes for example Airbnb uh
Tinder Google and uh well like popular
applications uh and uh they rewrite
their applications in kotlin and use
Scotland features and then they have
escaped kotlin it's like a complete mess
yeah have you I've noticed so I've
noticed that you're quite active on the
jedx project I don't know if other
people have noticed that but is that
something that you use pretty frequently
yeah and actually uh this tool is used
by the scanner and it's like super
important if everything is correctly
they compiled like if the code is
sophisticated it's okay but it should be
like compilable uh there should be like
correct references and uh
because finding a vulnerability it's
like a number of of actions of event of
events and uh like the code flow should
be like super correct and if it's not
correct like one of a hundred of uh
like important code lines is uh
corrupted the vulnerability it will be
missed and that's why I'm building in
like a tradix developer like hey guy
please fix me a specifically
detect the vulnerability
yeah yeah that's that's awesome that's
exactly what I've noticed is like I'll
be hacking on something and I'll have
some like weird behavior in Gen X and I
I also use Gen X as my main decompiler
but I don't do the same automated level
of scanning that you do however when
something fails to decompile oftentimes
I'll go and I'll look and I'll see
either you have a ticket open for it for
him to fix or it's just been fixed and I
need to update my version of jet X so
that's really uh that's really an
awesome thing to see where someone from
the community is interacting back and
forth with the tool Creator to actually
improve the tool in real time
yeah I'm actually I feel always like um
not angry but no when some guys report
the vulnerabilities about UI issues like
uh like the video is not correct and I'm
thinking it's like open search Project I
think I could be working on like the
compilation vulnerabilities but it's
working
she's working on UI issues why you care
about this
So speaking of the UI do you do you use
like when you use Gen X
um I guess maybe let me split this into
two questions so uh let's say for your
personal hacking not oversecured like
automatic automatic flow are you using
jet X when you decompile apps just
generally across the board of course
like only and I never try it any other
compilers
cool and then are you using the GUI much
or do you open it in like a separate
editor maybe maybe we can you could walk
me through sort of what your hacking
flow looks like if you're approaching
like just a one-off mobile app
so actually first of all I'm scanning's
application using over secure it and
then I'm uh looking for vulnerabilities
uh uh that it found
and um I didn't do like manual review
like sometimes I need to cover like all
the vulnerabilities like it's our
customer and we need to verify like
manually verify if everything is correct
no vulnerabilities I missed and that's
why I'm coming like a chicken everything
is correct uh no like uh corrupted code
flows
no the compilation issues and uh yeah
I'm like shaking all exported companions
uh I'm checking like clipboard
notification handling
um
like everything
like Local web services uh web servers
and so on
but uh like if I'm
manually hacking just for fun or just
because I didn't hack for a long time
and I want to come back to my roots
I'm like a chicken with using over
security and then I'm opening it in yeah
and uh
yeah
yeah okay cool yeah so it could be like
a simple vulnerability and I don't open
uh judics at all but sometimes if it's a
tricky vulnerability there are like uh
tricky conditions so I'm opening it and
uh judics yes
got it okay so why don't you tell me
we've talked about oversecured we
mentioned it a couple times but why
don't you talk a little bit about that
because it sounds like generally as you
were doing hacking it was sort of a
natural progression to create the
product and company that oversecured is
right
yep
so uh I was doing bug Bounty hacking
and I was looking for vulnerabilities
and many applications and I was like
lazy to do everything once again
manually
because they're like uh uh thousands of
files and I need to like again and again
go through like all the sources grab the
same stuff
and it was like super boring to do that
like manually and that's why I created a
tool and it was it better better and
better
in in 20
19 Google launched it's about variety
programs that called the Google Play
security Rewards program and uh I became
like number one hacker in this program
because they started paying like three
thousand dollars for every vulnerability
found in a super popular application and
like Google guys was asking me like what
do you think about this like before that
uh because before that that introduction
uh they had like uh
15 applications in scope and uh they
were asking me like how do you think we
should extend our program and I I told
maybe we need to add vendors like Google
apps or Google apps or someone else like
Samsung apps
um in the totally agent like all
applications that I have a hundred
million of its installations increasing
remarks three times at all guys you go
into background
they didn't believe me yep and um
I like started reports in a lot of
vulnerabilities and they started paying
a lot and uh like uh saying like a
privately
like it was our mistake that the uh
start to pay like three thousand dollars
and right now they're paying one
thousand dollars for such
vulnerabilities
yeah it's true I noticed that that they
dropped it down after they uh after a
little while after after you had farmed
them like crazy that that's really
really crazy so for those who don't know
uh you know vrp basically said any
application that was what was it over 1
million installs or
it's about 10 million installs
uh a hundred million and 100 billion is
there like uh 500 of such applications
right so basically any vulnerability
that affects any of those applications
Google vulnerability Rewards program
would pay you an additional Bounty even
if you reported it to the original app
right yep so actually
um I didn't like reporting it to the
developer because uh several policy
that uh was saying like if a company has
a back Bounty or vulnerability
disclosure program you need to report it
to them first wait until it's fixed and
it it was taken like months uh until you
get reward and uh that's why reporting
it's like directly to Google it's like
more profitable because you get in a
reward within I don't know like two
weeks and you're not waiting you're not
having like a backlog of vulnerabilities
you're not tracking because
I cannot say like I had a good
experience with developers because they
like don't care in Google uh like uh
pushing on developers and forcing them
to fix the vulnerability but when you as
a researcher reports in it to a
developers they like don't care and they
say like okay we're fixing it but
actually they not fixing it or they will
be fixing after a year so it's like a
very annoying and I like the reports in
vulnerabilities to Google
so what uh when you when you find bugs
in apps that are in that you know 500
plus cohort now you report it directly
to the company or do you still report it
directly to Google or what what does the
process look like now so you uh you have
to Google if uh the company has a bounty
or vgp program
and if they have you report it directly
to them if uh they don't you report it
to Google
and they start their own process of
validation in reverting you for this
got it got it okay so would you say that
like a lot of the people the the
companies and apps that you were finding
a lot of bugs on that you've now
assigned them as clients onto
oversecured if actually not all of them
because
this program was only a push to start
the company because I have I had like
friends that started their own companies
in cyber security and they pinged me
like saying like you have good scanner
you have a good business idea so start
your company and I was like starting a
company it's like where like paying
taxes like how it doesn't work yeah
yeah and uh when Google rewarded me like
if it's in I believe four or five months
of work within almost a million of
dollars I started like wow yeah like
everyone is vulnerable I got the
confirmation like even super popular
apps are vulnerable and right now I have
money to start my company fante version
by myself but strap it
yeah and um I did it
I came to America open a bank account
registered in the company and wow
delivery based company
oh that's amazing that I mean you really
it's awesome to see I love seeing when
bug bounty hunters especially but
generally just security researchers are
able to turn one of their like personal
toolings into a company like this
because there's so many smart people who
are building so many awesome security
related products and a lot of times it's
just for like personal use just like
what you were doing like this was just
to save time and effort uh by making
your scanning a lot easier so that you
could just throw in a nap and do all
your checks at one time and you could
just turn that into a product and help
other companies you know automatically
just they sign up and they pay you and
and get that coverage yeah but actually
I had no any idea like how business
Works uh then it appears that selling to
B2B is like super hard because even if
you like completely disrupt a company if
you like give them a good report uh they
fix the vulnerabilities they say thank
you Alleluia like yourself
anyway they need budgets like for your
tool and you need to talk
um it doesn't happen immediately like if
you hack them this year maybe in next
year they assign budgets like to buy
your tool yeah oh wow it's like super
long process yes yeah almost like the
triage process where you're waiting for
bodies
that's awesome
um so you had mentioned that uh you
disclosed to reports and um I think one
of those that I I have bookmarked and I
go back to all the time
is uh this this uh this report that you
call I think it's golden Android
techniques for URL uh parsing bypasses
or something like that
um what made you want to publish that
because that is just such an awesome
resource for people don't know this is
uh essentially I think it's four
different
um three or four different tricks that
you you know published for how uh
Android will be parsing URLs or
oftentimes apps will Implement parsing
URLs that are implicitly vulnerable to
parsing problems where you can either
pass in a different host or if they do
you know dot get hosts then it'll
respond with a different host but if
they were to do a string check then it's
different and so
um I think those are really really
awesome checks because I I reference
them all the time but what made you want
to publish that because this was
many years ago right this was 2018. um
so I think you were quite ahead of sort
of the the mobile security publishing
curve at that point
yeah actually this uh this is uh
reported in our blog in over secure
block I believe the article is uh like
attack vectors on The View or something
like that so there are like extended
techniques and uh extended ways of
hacking of securing yeah but
um I always publish like I don't have
any like hidden knowledge that I use
when it's dark
secrets your secret script folder I
don't actually have any hacking Secrets
um and I always published everything I
know like maybe I know a way of hacking
something but it's like uh super small
to publish uh and it's super small for
an article but I always posted
everything I know if it's if I consider
it's interesting because I think it's
like good for our world because there
are only a few mobile hackers and I have
like uh I don't know a hundred points in
my mobile hiking so I can push someone
else like to I don't know 20 or 250 or
to maybe
850. can you talk about it yeah because
like companies they don't know about
mobile vulnerabilities and when I
disclose the reports I like push them
and I believe they
started to know that there are mobile
bugs and how they look like
yeah absolutely I mean I think so many
people see mobile as sort of just
another proxy for API hacking or web
hacking where they just use it to get
endpoints exactly and that's kind of it
and that that's cool like you know that
is there's certainly vulnerabilities
there but I I think there's just so much
more depth when you're going to the real
like the level that you and I often go
to where it's you're looking for
activities you're looking for intents
you're looking for uh providers and and
all sorts of different like Android
specific components to find those real
like Android specific vulnerabilities
um that provide so much more impact than
just you know finding an eye door or
whatever well not always but oftentimes
that's cool um and so you mentioned your
uh the oversecured blog posts uh this is
another thing I have a bunch of these
bookmarked
um I've actually used over secured a
couple times to scan apps and one of the
things I really like is that it will
link out to the different blog posts
about different findings that it has so
if it finds uh you know access to
protected components it'll say hey
here's a link to the blog post where you
can read all about in depth you know
what does this look like uh you know
what is an export scenario look like how
can you identify these types of things
what's actually going wrong how can you
fix it like it's a huge huge resource
have you found that uh there are things
that you end up referencing in your own
blog posts while while you're hacking or
is that sort of just something that
you've written down and published in
just goes out there
um so all the blog posts are there like
results of hacking
and uh I like uh Kaka like previously I
was hacking like a number of
applications and I was looking like
common uh like uh common patterns of
vulnerabilities and I created Like rules
for detection and then I started
detecting it and right now I'm like
extending and extended and extending uh
the rule base
and um like right now I'm hunting for
like a new vulnerability patterns
because like uh don't know any other
patterns and that's why I like taking
the sources checking it everything if it
was your question
yeah yeah no totally I I was gonna ask
something about this as well because I
think one of the things that I felt as
well is that over time uh mobile hacking
like there's there's not many new
vulnerabilities that I see coming up
it's a lot of the same types of patterns
and the same types of vulnerabilities
that are appearing again and again have
you noticed
any new common issues or things that you
are seeing a lot more now that you
didn't used to see or is it kind of a
lot of the same
um
the last vulnerability like category
about two years ago in Android and for
iOS I'm like uh it's like a big house
here and like right now researching and
I'm like actively adding new categories
to iOS because it's like a research
sphere
but coming back to Android
um
so I think everything is linked because
uh like you have uh your your eye person
and maybe like a new research gives you
like a new way to hack your right person
or like bypass some checks and uh so on
and that's why like there are existing
articles there are existing researchers
and there are existing positive
vulnerabilities about like for example
you're a person but you find like a
I don't know epic slash attack and uh
it's like a new research and you're
bypassing a lot of new checks and it's
like a type of uh like all the dark but
it's like a new attack and like the
dancer because it was previously there
are like uh existing categories but it's
like anyway it's new
yeah okay so it sounds like a lot of
like now as you've continued to go
you've sort of branched into the at the
iOS sphere now just because it's a whole
new space it's a whole new area of
research it's all new you know
everything have you found that a lot of
things that worked on Android also have
sort of like a parallel into iOS or they
work there but in a different way
um
I believe there are like uh
80 percent of uh intersected categories
in Android and iOS but the biggest
problem of Android like previously and
the biggest problem of iOS right now is
that there are like two types of iOS
security
um first uh type of higher Securities
like NCR group that they hack like
everything into the system of building
chains the compiling everything uh
reversing like assemblers and the second
type of Fire Security it's like uh
running an application an emulator
chicken like uh kitchen flux and so on
yeah there should be like uh like a
different like the right type of
yes security that like doing uh like
normal level vulnerabilitation chicken
deep links it's not like a super
critical vulnerability that giving you a
root on the device but anyway you need
to protect uh the application and you
need to do in like a more deeply
yeah okay and have you have you done any
of that like deep level decompiling type
of research on iOS because when I think
about iOS hacking I think that there's a
really large section of it that is
essentially zero day research and
looking for bugs that can be used for
jailbreaking the system because it's not
like it's not easy to root it by default
is that something that you've spent any
time looking at or is it primarily the
applications themselves
so actually we're not the compiler the
compiling it because there's no like a
good way to get sources from a Us
application and that's why this for
example with our customers we go in with
Android and then we say like we also
secure iOS applications and we sign like
ngas they given sources and they like uh
super I don't know
afraid to give sources because uh they
say like we never did that before but I
say yeah okay you're on the right
application it's not obfuscated it's
like uh by default it's open sources
your address application and what's the
matter to uh
I I love I love that that Strat because
like so many people don't realize that
you could just decompile an Android
that's actually one of the things that I
love the most about Android app hacking
is I'm like a real I'm a source code
person I like reading the code and
understanding how it works and having it
all right in front of me in like an
application that you could just take
apart you know how everything works
there's no black magic it's just what
you see is what you get I I love that
approach to hacking uh and that's always
one of the things that's really like
pushed me away from IOS is that you
don't get that same level of you know
understanding and readability a lot it's
so much more obfuscated you have to do
you know it's reassembly and all this
stuff
um has that been a challenge for you as
well when when moving into the iOS space
um so
actually I didn't hack like pure IPA
applications like I'm not taking it like
I never took an EPA file and I checked
for vulnerabilities uh normally I took
for example Android application check
like uh deep links and then I try to
apply them to zayas application and
sometimes it worked like there's a
security secure check in Android
application but there's no checks in iOS
application and this is
applications and the second Vector is uh
like uh I took sources and uh like uh
checked for vulnerabilities adopted the
scanner to it then
let's go like it worked
but it's like a big problem for us like
uh as uh for a company securing your
supplications like we
because we when we developed a scanner
for Android we like taking a lot of
applications we can analyze we can get
statistics
we can check how like some speed like
like new experimental rules work what's
the output
you cannot do the same and that's why we
like uh asking our customers hello guys
uh are you okay to like um like we don't
store sources and that's why uh they
need to like share resources I like via
email or via a link with us and that's
why we analyzing it
and like engine rules checking if
something is wrong and there are like
undetected vulnerabilities
yeah so it's harder with iOS
um that's really interesting it's a
whole different problem space like yeah
I I really take my hat off to the people
who do iOS hacking all the time because
it's it's it's a whole different Beast
compared to Android I honestly think
Android is quite a bit easier
um so stepping off of that actually
um lots of people reach out they always
want to be getting into Mobile hacking
I'm sure this is something that people
probably ask you as well but what do you
have any tips or recommendations or
things that you would suggest to people
who are new to maybe their their
experienced hackers but they're new to
mobile hacking and they don't really
know where to start
um I would recommend like taking old
application like this and also disclosed
vulnerabilities and trying to reproduce
some vulnerabilities chicken locks to
check in what's going on and like uh
touching the vulnerability with your
hands but I think it's like um
like a bit harder to get into Mobile
security because when you hack in web
you can like put xss Vector like super
easy and you don't know to
to know like many things but when you
hack uh mobile applications you need to
know like uh Android context or iOS
context then you need to read the
sources and like Additionally you need
to read the compiled sources and
sometimes it's harder than reading like
a normal not applicated sources and
that's why is there like a number of
things you need to learn before you
get unsuccessful in Mobile hacking and
it would take some time
and it would take like a lot of efforts
from a person who wants to start mobile
hacking but um if this skill is uh
passed then you will be getting like a
lot of money from bug bounties because
like everyone is vulnerable and there
are a lot of vulnerabilities in uh zero
like maybe five percent with you and if
you compare it to the background is uh
they're like 500 people campaign
so true that's and that hasn't really
changed much either when I first got
into bug Bounty everybody was like oh
you you do mobile hacking like you
should you should hack on mobile because
nobody does mobile hacking and uh you
know five years later it's very little
has changed so so yeah absolutely I'll
totally Echo that
um I love that that piece that you
mentioned about uh like retesting
vulnerabilities do you have uh any ways
that you identify you know all the old
reports or stuff that people have
published is are you on Twitter a lot
like where where do you find uh reports
to to go read and reproduce
um I believe there are a lot of uh
GitHub representations that contain
links to like different disclosed
vulnerabilities to articles and uh like
a person needs to like check maybe they
don't understand everything immediately
but uh it's like you're reading
something understanding something and
then coming again and and again again in
in the loop until you get everything
awesome had you ever done any Java
programming before you started hacking
on mobile
um
uh like
uh the simple answer is no but when I
was like a Schoolboy I was uh I I wanted
to like to create a lot of projects
um and I let's say I I didn't know
anything about parents I was like 10
years old and I wanted to create like my
own website so
it had to be completely free no lights
in this no everything in like people
people have really shared like because
there are stuff on that website
it was really passionate about this idea
and I I don't know why but I thought
that I need to learn PHP and C plus plus
it's a very interesting selection of
languages
so those are your first two and then you
kind of just yeah I think one of the one
of the really challenging things about
mobile is that it's especially Android
like you kind of almost need to know how
to read code you don't necessarily need
to know how to write it but being able
to read and understand what a code
snippet is doing is really really
important especially for the deeper
types of vulnerabilities that we're
talking about not just AI or API uh you
know scanning or looking at the requests
in burp or whatever
but actually finding like figuring out
what the app is doing
um requires some some level of
understanding and I think that could be
a big hurdle uh do you ever have to
spend time like learning about new so
like for instance kotlin did you have to
do a deep dive on how kotlin works and
stuff in order to to figure that out or
did you kind of just
adapt your tooling to figure out you
know what does kotlin look like at the
end of compilation and just you know
make it work with how it is
um I think I never adopted the scanner
to kotlin because when kotlin is
compiled to uh uh byte code then it's
the compiled to Java code and it's like
uh it's the same to like a normal Java
code but there's a lot of uh different
checks and uh like uh cotton stuff but
it's not important from vulnerability
detection perspective
um yes there are a lot of like uh
synthetic lashes closures that I
compiled to Java classes and they look
like uh yeah like a complete mess when
the compound but anyway it's not a big
problem for vulnerability detection
nice okay that's really cool man I'd
love to I'd love to pick your brain uh
in depth about how how your whole
product works but I don't wanna I don't
wanna board people and uh and have to
bleep out a bunch of this episode so um
yeah we'll uh we'll we'll leave the
super technical stuffer off here but um
cool man I I think that was like most of
the questions that I had
um was there anything else that you
wanted to sort of shout out or um any
you know your company your website your
Twitter anything like that
um you can add uh links to my profiles
and uh yeah podcast so absolutely you
don't care for all um all the Bingo
Twitter website and the blog
perfect also we can add like some most
popular repositories that contain uh
like uh a set of disclosed
vulnerabilities and set of Articles uh
they're like many of my uh
vulnerabilities in my many of my
articles but anyways there are like like
uh
um a lot of uh different ones so you can
share it with the guys and they can
start at the mobile hacking
awesome perfect yes we'll we'll put
those links uh down in the description
um you can find uh links to baggy Pro's
uh profiles the over skirt website um
the overscript blogs a bunch of blog
posts and and mobile security write-ups
and uh if mobile hacking is something
that you're looking to get into that is
an awesome place to start uh like I said
those are some of the best mobile
hacking resources that are out there
especially that are like up to date and
modern and Bug Bounty focused and that
kind of stuff so
um awesome dude this was uh this was
this was great I know it's early over in
uh in Asia or Japan or wherever wherever
you're currently at right now so I
appreciate you waking up at the crack of
dawn and uh chugging two coffees before
before you got you got on here to talk
with me and uh hopefully you could get a
little more sleep after this yeah
um
I couldn't talk like oh my God
do you want to get a coffee or like yeah
I'm gonna I'm gonna go to the coffee
shop I'll be right back
yeah because yesterday landed at 1am and
I woke up at the
7 50 a.m so
all right well then you you should go
back to sleep you've done enough brains
that big of mobile Securities thanks
very much so our game was awesome
talking with you all right peace
[Music]